[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以JavaScript是一种面向对象的编程语言
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So JavaScript is an object-oriented programming language
但是它所认为的对象与大多数
which, but what it thinks an object is is different from the most
其他面向对象的语言。
other object-oriented languages.
在JavaScript中，对象只是属性的动态集合。
In JavaScript, an object is simply a dynamic collection of properties.
每个属性都有一个键字符串，该字符串在该对象中是唯一的，并且
Every property has a key string that is unique within that object, and
该键字符串将与任何值关联。
that key string will be associated with any value.
可以使用点表示法或从对象中获取属性
You can get a property from an object by using the dot notation or
括号表示法，它们在某些情况下可以互换使用。
the bracket notation, they can be used, in some cases, interchangeably.
如果括号包含作为字符串的表达式，
If the bracket contains an expression which is a string,
与名称相同，那么您将获得相同的属性。
which is the same as a name, then you'll get the same property.
这使得在不使用反射API的情况下动态获取东西成为可能。
That makes it possible to dynamically get at things without use of a reflection API.
只需指定对象的属性，即可设置这些属性。
You can set of properties of an object simply by assigning to those properties.
您可以简单地通过赋值来添加新属性或修改旧属性，
You can add new properties or modify old properties simply by assignment,
您还可以使用删除操作符从对象中删除属性。
and you can also delete properties from an object using a delete operator.
虽然，我很少看到这个用过。
Although, I very rarely see this used.
一般来说，一旦一个物体被制造出来，它就会保留它的东西。
Generally, once an object is made, it keeps its stuff.
JavaScript中的一个设计错误是键必须是字符串。
One design mistake in JavaScript is that the keys must be strings.
如果它们可以有任何价值，那会更好，但它们不是。
It would've been better if they could've been any value, but they're not.
因此您可以将任何类型传递到括号中，
So you can pass any type into the brackets,
JavaScript会将其转换为字符串。
JavaScript will turn that into a string.
所以bean，实际上，值必须是字符串。
So the beans, effectively, the values have to be strings.
我们有一个非常好的对象文字表示法，
We have a very nice object literal notation,
JavaScript的对象文字表示法是Jason的灵感来源
JavaScript's object literal notation was the inspiration for the Jason
数据交换格式，世界上最受欢迎的数据交换格式。
data interchange format, the world's most loved data interchange format.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：你有一个花括号来标识对象，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: You've got curly braces that identify the object,
然后，您已经在对象中获得了命名字段或属性。
then you've got named fields or properties within the object.
如果名称是有效的标识符，则不必在名称两边加上引号。
You don't have to put quotes around the names if the names are valid identifiers.
如果它们不是标识符，则需要用引号将它们括起来。
If they are not identifiers, then you need to put the quotes around them.
所以大多数面向对象的编程语言都是经典的。
So most object oriented programming languages are classical.
它们都是关于创建类，其中对象是类的实例，并且
They're all about making classes where objects are instances of classes and
类从其他类继承。
classes inherit from other classes.
JavaScript有一个更简单，更高级的设计，
JavaScript has a much simpler, much more highly evolved design,
它基于原型，其中对象从对象继承并
which is based on prototypes where objects inherit from objects and
就是这样，没有课。
that's it, there are no classes.
这是我们从自我那里得到的想法，
This was the idea that we got from the self,
这比闲聊好多了。
which was an improvement over small talk.
但这确实是一个有争议的想法，大多数写这篇文章的人
But it's a really controversial idea and most people who are writing in this
语言不明白这到底是怎么回事，但我们会讨论一下。
language do not understand how this really works, but we're gonna talk about it.
所以使用原型实际上是非常容易的。
So working with prototypes is actually very easy.
您可以使用任何可用的技术来制作您喜欢的对象
You make an object that you like using any of the techniques available for
制作一个物体。
making an object.
可以创建从对象继承的新实例，然后可以
You can create new instances that inherit from the object, and then you can
通过指定新属性或替换属性来自定义新实例。
customize the new instances by assigning new properties or replacing properties.
您必须在中执行的分类和分类操作
The classification and taxonomy operations that you have to do in
一个经典的系统是不必要的，结果是一个巨大的胜利。
a classical system aren't necessary, which turns out to be a huge win.
所以如果你在一个经典的系统中工作，当你开始时，
So if you're working in a classical system, when you start off,
你必须对所有的物体进行分类。
you have to classify all the objects.
你必须弄清楚所有的物体是什么，它们是由什么组成的，
You have to figure out what are all the objects, what are they composed of,
它们之间有什么关系？
how are they related?
然后你做了一个分类法，在这个分类法中你找出了要继承的东西
Then you make a taxonomy in which you figure out what's going to inherit from
什么，什么要实现什么，这是一个非常复杂的层次结构。
what, what's gonna implement what, and it's a really complicated hierarchy.
通常，你在项目中的某一点上做这项工作，通常，
Usually, you're doing that work at the point in the project, usually,
一开始
the beginning,
我们对象系统实际上是如何工作的了解最少。
we have the least understanding of how the object system's actually gonna work.
这意味着几乎可以肯定你会弄错
Which means it's almost certain that you're gonna get it wrong and
你看，东西组合得不好。
you see that in that things don't compose properly.
你就是不能，它们不起作用。
You just can't, they don't work.
你发现自己希望他们有多重继承，
You find yourself wishing they had multiple inheritance,
因为没有办法从这里到那里。
cuz there's no way to get from here to there.
当你把越来越多的类放在上面的时候，
And as you layer in more and more classes on top,
你发现破碎开始渗透到所有更高的层面，然后
you find that that brokenness starts to seep up into all the higher layers, and
最终达到这样一个点，它已经坏到你必须重构的地步，
eventually reach the point where it's so broken that you have to refactor,
这意味着必须把所有的东西都撕碎，然后再重新组装起来。
which means have to tear it all apart and put it back together again.
这真的很危险，因为它有可能永远不会回到一起
Which is really dangerous, cuz there's a chance it might not ever go back together
同样，所有这些都是由于类的耦合。
again, and all of that is due to the coupling of classes.
如果你不上课，
And if you get rid of classes,
你不需要做任何这些，这真的很了不起。
you don't have to do any of that, which is really quite remarkable.
因此JavaScript提供的模型有时称为委托，
So the model that JavaScript provides is sometimes called delegation,
一个对象只能做它能做的事情
where an object can only do what it can do and
如果在那里，如果它被要求做一些它不能做的事情，
if there if it's asked to do something that it can't do,
它将指定另一个对象来代表它完成工作。
it will designate another object to do that work on its behalf.
这也称为差异继承，其中每个对象仅
This is also called differential inheritance, where each object will only
包含将其与其继承的对象区分开来的材料。
contain the material which distinguishes it from the object that it inherits from.
JavaScript中用于创建新对象的原语是object dot create，
The primitive in JavaScript for making a new object is object dot create,
我们将一个对象传递给它，不幸的是，这个对象被称为原型，并且
where we pass it an object, which unfortunately is called a prototype, and
我们创建了一个继承旧对象的新对象。
we make a new object that inherits from the old one.
这里的Prototype这个词是有问题的，因为它太过载了。
The word prototype here is problematic because it's so overloaded.
它的意思是，这是我们想要继承的对象。
All it means is, this is the object that we want to inherit from.
所以让我们用图表来描述一下。
So let's diagram this.
我要制作一个叫做母亲的物体，它有两个属性，
I'm gonna make up an object called mother, which will have two properties,
a和b，其值为1和2。
a and b, whose values will be 1 and 2.
这就是创建的数据结构。
And this is the data structure that is created.
所以我们有我们的键值对和
So we've got our key value pairs and
我们也有指向object.prototype的不可见指针。
we also have invisible pointer to object.prototype.
所以无论何时你把一个对象变成文字，
So whenever you make an object literal,
它最终将从object.prototype继承。
it will ultimately inherit from object.prototype.
如果我做了一个女儿对象，
Then if I make a daughter object,
我将使用object.创建母亲，因此我现在有了一个女儿。
I'll use object.create mother, so I now have a daughter.
所以我得到了一个空的女儿对象，它是从母亲那里继承的。
So I've got an empty daughter object which inherits from mother.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以，如果我说dayter.b+2，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So if I say daughter.b + 2,
原来这里没有价值。
originally there is no value here.
所以我们得到了b的继承值，然后我们把2加到它上面，
So we get the inherited value of b, then we add two to it and
把它储存在女儿身上。
store it in the daughter.
因此，存储操作将始终进入最顶层的对象，但是
So storing operations will always go into the top most object, but
阅读操作可以一直沿着原型链进行。
reading operations can go all the way down the prototype chain.
我们可以让这些锁链走多长时间都行。
And we can have these chains go as long as you want.
通常，这种语言中的链往往非常浅。
Generally, chains in this language tend to be very shallow.
我们不会像你在古典语言中看到的那样深层次，但是
We don't get the deep hierarchies that you tend to see in classical languages but
如果你想深入，你可以。
if you wanna go deep, you can.
然后，我们可以向子对象添加材质
Then, we can add material to the daughter object
它与母对象没有关系，所以我们可以添加更多的内容。
which has no relation to the mother object, so we can add more stuff.
所以一般来说，我们使用它的方式是母对象将在哪里
So generally, the way we'll use this is the mother object will be where
我们放入方法，然后实例将继承这些方法，好吗？
we put the methods, and then the instances will inherit those methods, okay?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：还有一个表单Object.create(Null)，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: There's also a form Object.create (null),
这将使对象没有继承任何东西。
which will make an object that inherits nothing.
因此，您得到的对象不是从object.prototype继承的。
So you get an object that does not inherit from object.prototype.
如果你想做点什么，这是很方便的
This is handy if you want to make something which is just
一个装满东西的容器而你不想
a container of stuff and you don't want to
被你可能从object.prototype继承来的东西弄糊涂了。
be confused by stuff that you might inherit from object.prototype.
因此，这将更像一个哈希表。
So this will act much more like a hash table.